Personal Information

Name Alexander Toschev Phd.

Passport Russia

Date of birth 17 May 1989

Contacts atoschev@kpfu.ru (preferred), sanchis.no@gmail.com

Research Gate https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Alexander_Toschev3

Personal Blog http://toschev.me

Personal Profile

Strengths Excellent team player; good in teaching; good in critical situations; good at introducing something new; good in communication; self-motivated; at

critical unresolvable situations produces magic and fix it; ability to work under pressure; good leader

Weaknesses

Unable to work for a long time for a trivial tasks; hard to work alone; hard to work with demotivated team, when team can't be motivated

Computing Professional Experience

current Software and solution Team lead in ICL services (formerly known as Fujitsu GDC Russia), Kazan, Russian Federation.

Retail software and hardware development and design

current **Associate professor at Kazan Federal University**, Kazan, Russian Federation, Kazan, Russian Federation.

Cognition framework development

2016 **Phd student at Kazan Federal University**, Kazan, Russian Federation, Kazan, Russian Federation.

Cognition framework development

2014 Software and solution Architect in ICL Services (formerly known as Fujitsu GDC Russia, Distributed retail system development.

2009 Software and solution Developer in ICL Services (formerly known as Fujitsu GDC Russia), Distributed logistic system development.

Education Background

2011 Master degree in computer science, Kazan Federal University, Russia, Faculty of calculated mathematics and cybernetics, Thesis: Intelligent automation system for incident solving.

2011 Professional translator, Kazan Federal University, Russia, Faculty of linguistic.

2015 **Phd degree in computer science**, *Kazan Federal University, Russia*, Faculty of computer system, Planned on December 2015.

Teaching Experience

2012-Now, Kazan Federal University Software Architecture

2012-Now, Kazan Federal University Object Oriented Programming

Projects

Thinking-Understanding (2012-now) Intelligent system for automatic incident processing

Singularity

arity $\,$ 3D game engine on DirectX 7 with programming shaders in C++

(2010)

Menta Automatic application construction via Natural Language processing

IDP Semantic Document Processing

Cybervisor Data flow integration with several systems written in C++

Language Competence

Russian mother language English Technical: good;

Written: good; Spoken: good

Professional Training

2015 Communication Skills

2009 Software Architect

and

2008 OpenMP and Intel MPI development

Computing Knowledge

Operating Microsoft Windows, Linux, Mac OS Programming C++, C#, Java, Scala, VB, Delphi,

Systems Pascal, VB.NET, T-SQL

Databases SQL, JDBC, DB2, Access, Post- Web Publishing HTML, XML, JavaScript, jQuery

greSQL, Neo4j, HypergraphDB

Software Design UML, Problem Frames Tools Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook,

Visio, Dream weaver, ArgoUML, Vi-

Specification sual Paradigm

Profiles VisualVM, .NET Profiler Unmanaged Code Analyst profiler

Journal papers

Toshchev A., Talanov M. - Computational emotional thinking and virtual neurotransmitters, International Journal of Synthetic Emotions (IJSE), 2014, 05/2014

Toshchev A., Talanov M. - Coping and High Level Emotions Aspects of Computational Emotional Thinking, International Journal of Synthetic Emotions (IJSE) 2015, 06/2015

Conferences and Workshops

Toshchev A., Talanov M. - Thinking Lifecycle as an Implementation of Machine Understanding in Software Maintenance Automation Domain, Agent and Multi- Agent Systems: Technologies and Applications: 9th KES International Confer- ence, KES-AMSTA 2015 Sorrento, Italy, June 2015, Proceedings (Smart Innovation, Systems and Technologies), Sorento, Italy, 2015

Toshchev A. - Thinking model and machine understanding in automated user request processing, CEUR Workshop Proceedings (RCDL-2014), Dubna, Russia, 2014

Toshchev A. Talanov M. - ARCHITECTURE AND REALIZATION OF IN- TELLECTUAL AGENT FOR AUTOMATIC INCIDENT PROCESSING US- ING THE ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE AND SEMANTIC NETWORKS, Electronic libraries , Kazan, Russia, 2014

Toshchev A. Talanov M. Krehov A. Khasianov A. - *Thinking-Understanding approach in IT maintenance domain automation*, Global Journal on Technology (WCIT-2012) , Barcelona, Spain, 2012

Conference and Workshop Activities

2012 WCIT

2014 RCDL

2013 AINL

2015 AMSTA

2016 AMSTA

2017 DESE

2017 AMSTA